<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A proclamation set forth by Sir Iames Carroll Knight Maior of the Citty of Dublin</title>
            <author>Dublin (Ireland). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1612</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 24 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A04095</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 14164</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S121268</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99856452</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99856452</idno>
            <idno type="VID">22002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A04095)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 22002)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 963:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A proclamation set forth by Sir Iames Carroll Knight Maior of the Citty of Dublin</title>
                  <author>Dublin (Ireland). Lord Mayor.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>2 sheets   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Iohn Franckton printer and stationer to the Kings Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1612.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Enforcing certain laws--STC.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Jesuits --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Catholics --  Ireland --  Legal statutes, laws, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  Proclamations --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:22002:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>❀ A PROCLAMATION SET forth by Sir Iames Carroll Knight Maior <hi>of the Citty of Dublin.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Here great inconuenience dayly happeneth vnto this Citty, by reaſon of ſundry diſloyall, wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked, &amp; malicious Perſons, whoe rather preferre their owne priuate vnlawefull deſires, and their priuate commodity &amp; profit, then by obſeruing of good Lawes and Orders, to procure y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> publicke commodity of the Inhabitants of the ſame, and doe by their vndutifull behauiour, indanger th<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>mſelues in the penalties and puniſhments of ſundry Lawes eſtabliſhed: Wher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſaid Maior intending the reformation of the ſame, hath thought good, aſwell by the ſpeciall commaundement and direction of the Right Honorable the Lord Deputy and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cell eſtabliſhed for this Kingdome, as alſo by the aduiſe of the ſaid Maior and his Aſſoſiats, the Magiſtrats of this Citty, to forewarne and giue knoweledge to ſuch as haue been y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> offendors, that they from henceforth ſhould not incurre the danger of the Lawes ordeyned for offences, which (by Gods permiſion) he intends to put in due execution.</p>
            <p>Firſt, the ſaid Maior by the ſpeciall comaundment and direction of the Right Honorable the Lord Deputy and Councell, doth in his Maieſties name ſtraightly charge and commaund all manner of Ieſuits and Seme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naries Prieſts, and other Prieſts authoriſed by the Sea of Rome, that are within the Citty of Dublin &amp; Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiſes thereof, contrary to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> effect of ſundrie Proclamations publiſhed in that behaulfe, doe forthwith remooue and departe from the ſaid Citty and Franchiſes, ſo as they nor any of them, nor any other of that kinde, be here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after found within any parte of the ſaide Citty or Franchiſes, at their perils: And further, the ſaid Maior by the comaundment and direction aforeſaid, doth in his Maieſties name ſtraightly charge and commaund all and euery Inhabitant, Houſehoulder, and other Perſon and Perſons whatſoeuer, dwelling within this Citty and Franchiſes thereof, that they nor any of them, doe from henceforth harbour, keepe, or receaue into any of their Houſes, any Ieſuit or other the Prieſts aforenamed: Nor ſhall ſuffer the ſaid Ieſuits or other Prieſts, or any of them, to vſe or excerciſe their Function contrary to the Lawes of this Realme, neither prrmit or ſuffer a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny meetings or aſſemblies of People in any of their Houſes or Chambers to heare the ſaide Ieſuits or other Prieſts excerciſe their ſaid Functions, vppon paine of impriſonment of euery ſuch offendor, till they and euery of them ſhalbe deliuered by due courſe of Lawe.</p>
            <p>Further the ſaid Maior doth in his Maieſties name ſtraightly charge and commaund all &amp; euery ſuch Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon und Perſons within this Citty and Subburbs, that doe preſume to teach and inſtruct Children or others in any kinde of Learning or Docterine, being not allowed and Lycenſed by the Lord Archbyſhopp of this Dio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, that they and euery of them doe forthwith forbeare to teach and inſtruct within this Citty and Franchi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, any Children or others, vntill they ſhalbe allowed and lycenſed by the ſaid Lord Archbyſhopp: And withal, that no Inhabitant or other Perſon whatſoeuer within this Citty &amp; Franchiſes, doe from henceforth permit or ſuffer any ſuch Teacher or Inſtruetor to teach within any of their Houſes and Chambers within this Citty &amp; Franchiſes, vppon paine of impriſonment and ſuch furthere puniſhment as may be inflicted vppon them, by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Lawes and ſtatutes of this Realme.</p>
            <p>Alſo the ſaid Maior in the Kings Maieſties name doth ſtraightly charge and commaund, that noe Perſon or Perſons, Inhabitants of this Citty or otherwiſe, ſhall vſe any for ſtaulling, regrating or ingroſing, to the hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derance of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Market of this Citty, in buying any Wheat, Mault, or other graine, Fleaſh, Fiſh, Butter, Eggs, Cheeſe, or any other Victualls, or Accates, before the ſame come to the ordinary and accuſtomed places for ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling thereof, there openly and publickly to be ſould, vppon paine of xx. s. and impriſonment: And that no In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitant in Fiſhtreete doe permit any Veales, Muttons, or other Fleaſh to be brought into their Houſes to be kept, for any Country Butcher, or other Perſon, to the preiudice &amp; diſfurniſhing of the Market, vppon paine of xx. daies impriſonment, aſwell to the Owner of the Houſe where ſuch Fleaſh ſhalbe found, as alſo to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of the Fleaſh, and alſo forfeiture of the ſaide Fleaſh.</p>
            <p>And the ſaide Maior doth by the aduiſe aforeſaid, ſtraightly charge and commaund, that no Perſon or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons Inhabitants of this Citty and Subburbs, ſhall from the xx. daie of Nouember next, ſuffer any ſingle-Woman to keepe his or their Tauerne in any ſorte, vppon paine of forfeiting and paying ten pounds, for euery ſuch offence, the one haulfe to this Citty, and the other haulfe to ſuch as ſhall enforme the ſame.</p>
            <p>And alſo the ſaid Maior ſeeing the great number of Firre &amp; Faggot Reekes, that are placed both within the Citty and alſo in the Subburbs, whereby great inconuenience may ariſe (if the ſame be not ſpeedely preuen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted:) The ſaid Maior by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> aduiſe aforeſaid, doth ſtraightly charge &amp; command all ſuch Perſons as haue now at this inſtant any ſuch Firre &amp; Faggot, or any other Fuell ſubiect to Firre within this Citty, to remooue the ſame by the xx. day of Nouember next, and that none ſhall make any manner of Firre, or Faggot-Reeks here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after, within the ſaide Citty, vppon paine of xl. s. for euery ſuch offence.</p>
            <p>And further that noe Firre or Faggot-Reekes as aforeſaid, ſhall continue or be made within ten Fathom of any Houſe or Tenement in the Subburbs of the Citty, after the ſaide xx. day of Nouember next, vppon the like paine of xl. s. And that no Stabler or other Perſon, from henceforth ſhall take any more for liuery of any Horſe at Hay &amp; Stable roome for euery xxiiii. houres, but vi. d. ſterling, vpon paine of of xiii. s. iiii. d. for euery offence.</p>
            <p>And further, for the auoiding of diuers other inconuenſences that may enſue, the ſaid Maior doth in like ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner charge and commaund, that all Country-Butchers comming to the Market of this Citty hereafter w<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Fleſh to be ſoulde, ſhall bring with them the Hides, Skins, and Tallowe, of al ſuch Beeues, Muttons, &amp; Veales, as they bring to be ſould, vppon paine of forfeiture of all ſuch Beeues, Muttons, or Veales ſo bought or ſould, &amp; that all ſuch Perſons ſhall bring the ſame to the Fiſhambles, there to be ſould, and not in the Streets out of the ſaid Shambles, as heretofore hath been accuſtomed, &amp; not to be ſould there before eight of the clocke, vpon paine of impriſonment as wel to the Buyer as to the Seller: And withall, that no free Butcher of this Citty, nor their Seruants, bee from hencefoorth found in the Country Shambles ſelling in groſe or by retayle, any
<pb facs="tcp:22002:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>Fleaſh vppon any market day, vppon paine of xl. s. ſterling, And withall, that the Country Butcher from hence-forth ſhall continue in the Country-Shambles euery Market day to ſell and retaile their Fleaſh from eight of the clock in the forenoone, vntill one in the afternoone, &amp; no longer, vpon pain of forfeiture of their ſaid fleaſh.</p>
            <p>And likewiſe that no Perſon or Perſons from hence-forth doe keepe any diſorder or miſcule in any part of this Citty and Subburbs, eſpetially vppon the Saboth daie, at any other day, by day or by night, vppon paine of ſuch puniſhment as are by the Lawes prouided: And withall, that no Perſon or Perſons doe from hence-forth plaie at Tennis, Stooleball or Cudgels, or vſe any kind of bodily excerciſe openly in any Street, Lane, or places within this Citty and Subburbs on the Sabboth day, vpon paine of impriſonment, &amp; that no Prentize or Seruant of any Cittizen be from henceforth founde playing within any Tenniſ-court or Bou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling-Allies within this Citty and Subburbs, vpon paine of three daies impriſonment in the Stocks to euery offendor for euery offence.</p>
            <p>Alſo the ſaid Maior by the aduiſe aforeſaid, doth ſtraightly charge &amp; commaund, that no Ale-wife or Seller of ſtrong Ale or Beere, ſhall ſell any ſtrong Ale or ſtrong Beere other then after the rate of one Lawfull ſealed Wine quart for a penny ſterling, vppon paine of forfeiture of ten ſhillings ſterling: and of ordinary Beere or Ale, two Wine quarts for a pennie ſterling, vppon the penaltie aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>And further, the ſaid Maior doth by the aduiſe aforeſaid, doth ſtraightly charge and command, that no In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitant of this Citty or Subburbs, ſhall vtter or ſell any Wine, Beere, or Ale, on any Saboth day vntill xi. of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> clock in the forenoone, and that during the ſame time no Cooke or other Perſon ſhall ſell any Fleaſh, Fiſh, or other dreſſed meats, either vpon Stalls or otherwiſe vppon paine of impriſonment for the ſpace of twenty daies, and forfeiture of the ſame ſo bought or ſould to be beſtowed vppon the poore Priſoners of the Caſ<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ell or Newgate, And that withall, no Perſon or Perſons, either Free or otherwiſe inhabiting within y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Franchiſes and Liberties of this Citty, ſhall from the xx. day of Nouember next, vtter or ſell either Ale or Beere in groſe or by retaile, without the liſence of the Maior of the ſaid Citty for the tyme being, firſt had and obtained in writing, vppon paine of forfeiture of xl. s. by euery offendor in this caſe, and impriſonment.</p>
            <p>Moreouer the ſaid Ma<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>or doth by the aduiſe aforeſaid, ſtraightly charge and commaund, that none of the Cittizens, Man or Woman, weare any Iriſh Apparell, or ſuch Apparell as is prohibited by the Lawes of this Realme, vppon paine of ſuch penalties as are by the ſame Lawes made and prouided: Alſo he further com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maundeth that no Cooke of this Citty or Subburbs, doe or ſhall ſel any kinde of Fleaſh or Fiſh, rawe or vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreſſed without Licence as aforeſaid, vppon paine of forfeiture of x. s. for euery offence, &amp; withal doth ſtraight<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly charge and commaund, that euery Man doe vſe and haue true waights and meaſures, according the Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dart, vppon paine of ſuch penalties and puniſhments as by the Lawes are in that caſe made &amp; prouided.</p>
            <p>And the ſaid Maior doth by the aduiſe aforeſaid, ſtraightly charge and commaund, that all Idell, ſturdy &amp; vacabond Beggers and other young Loiterers, aſwell men as woemen, hauing no Lawfull Trade to liue by, or Maſters to maintayne them, ſhall within xx. daies after the publiſhing hereof, auoide this Citty &amp; Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burbs, vppon paine of impriſonment for fortie daies, and after to be whipped, and baniſhed out of this Citty.</p>
            <p>And further, that no Perſon or Perſons doe or ſhall come into the Market, on any Market daie either to cheapen or buy any Graine before the Bell be roung in the common Hall, vppon paine of impriſonment of the offendors, at the diſcretion of the ſuid Maior, and forfeiture of two ſhillings ſterling by the offendor for euery offence: and that all Perſons which buy or ſell any Corne from henceforth within the Liberties, ſhall buy &amp; ſell by this meaſure &amp; not otherwiſe, <hi>viz.</hi> the Wheat Pecke ſealed to be three Buſhels of Wincheſter meaſure ſtrickt, and the Maulte meaſure to be the Briſtol-band-barrel ſtrickt, s. by euery offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dor in this nature. And for the better effecting hereof, the ſaid Maior hath cauſed xxx. Pecks for Wheat to be made and diſtributed into the ſeuerall Wardes of this Citty, for auoiding inconuenience and incertainty of the heaped Market Pecke heretofore vſed.</p>
            <p>And further, that no Perſon or Perſons of what qualitie or condition ſoeuer, ſhall ſell any Fleaſh, Fiſh, or any other Victuals or Accates within this Citty or Subburbs, except Hearbs and Fruite, which muſt not be ſould till after Sermon-time in the afternoone vppon y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Saboth daie, vppon paine of forfeiture of al ſuch Fleaſh, Fiſh, Victuals &amp; Accates: And that no Carmen, Carters, Bruers, or their Seruants, ſhall from the ſaid xx. daie of Nouember come or goe with any Ironbound-Cartes or Carres within the Walles of this Citty, vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pon paine of forfeiture of twelue pence ſterling for euery offence.</p>
            <p>Alſo the ſaid Maior by the aduiſe aforeſaid, chargeth and commaundeth, That no Perſon or Perſons ſhall from hencefoorth keepe any Swine, Cowes, or Cattell, within this Cittie, vppon forfeiture of xx. s. ſterling for euery time offending in this nature: and that no Swine be kept vnringed by any Perſon or Perſons in the Subburbs of this Citty, nor ſuffer to come within the Walles of this Cittie, vppon the like forfeiture.</p>
            <p>And further, that no Perſon or Perſons from henceforth ſhall vſe within this Cittie or Liberties thereof, the Trade of Broakage in Selling or Buying of any Remnants of Broadcloath, Stuffes, or other Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dities or Marchandize, vpon paine of forfeiture of fortie ſhillings ſterling by euerie offendor for euery time of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fending, and impriſonment during Maiſter Maiors pleaſure.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:22002:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p> And likewiſe where many vngodly, wicked, and ill diſpoſed Perſons lately comming out of England, and thers reſident in this Kingdome, doe vſe &amp; continue that moſt curſed and cruell trade of extreame intereſt and Vſury, by grinding the Face of the poore, in lending of Money at rates farre exceeding Iudaicall crueltie in that kinde: The ſaid Maior b<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the aduiſe aforeſaid, doth ſtraightly in his Maieſties name charge and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maund all manner of Perſon &amp; Perſons that heretofore haue vſed, or hereafter ſhall vſe that griping Trade of Vſury, in this Citty &amp; Franchiſes thereof, either by waie of intereſt to be repaid in Monie, or forfeiture of Paunes, to forbeare either for the time paſt, for which they can challenge anie intereſt for lone of their Moneis, or for the time to come to take aboue after the rate of x. li. in the Hundred <hi>per Annum,</hi> which is but by waie of tolleration onely, vppon paine and penaltie of ſuch Lawes as are eſtabliſhed againſt the ſame.</p>
            <p>And laſtely, the ſaid Maior purpoſing by the aduiſe aforeſaid, to put all the ſaid Lawes and Ordinances in due execution, hath cauſed this Proclamtion to be printed, that it maie bee ſo publique as none ſhall pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend Ignorance of it, and therefore commaundeth euery Alderman, Deputie Alderman, and Counſt able, in the ſaide Citty and Liberties, to buie on of theſe for his full and perfect direction in the execution hereof.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Dated at Dublin <date>the laſt day of October. <hi>1612.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Iames Carroll Maior Dublin.</signed> 
               <hi>GOD SAVE THE KING.</hi>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at Dublin by Iohn Franckton Printer and Stationer to <hi>the Kings Maieſtie. 1672.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
